Safeguard your GL accounts from
deletion.
In Business Central, it's possible to
delete an account from the general
ledger
even if there has been transactions on
it, as long as it has no balance and the
transactions do not belong to an income
year that is still open.
We recommend that you change some
settings to restrict when these
deletions can occur.
This is done on the general ledger setup
page.
Let's go there.
I bring up the search with Alt Q.
I type general ledger
setup
and I go to the general ledger setup
page.
Let me find the fields that I'm looking
for.
Here we have three fields that govern
the circumstances of GL account
deletion.
With the check GL account usage setting
we can block any attempt to delete a GL
account if the account is used in any
setup tables, like for example, if it's
specified in the posting setup.
The next two settings work in
combination with each other.
First if you have regulatory
requirements for how long you need to
store data
you want to first define that in the
check GL account deletion after field.
For example
if you must store data for 5 years
and your fiscal year follows the
calendar year
specify the date after which you don't
want deletions to occur.
For example if the current fiscal year
is 2023, which is still open by the way
and I need to store data for 5 years
meaning 2018 through 2022
I set the check GL account deletion
after to December 31st, 2017. This means
I can only delete the account if
transactions has happened before that
date.
Now, when I try to delete an account
with transactions in years 2018 through
2022, the system will ask me if I really
want to delete the account.
I can still do so if I want to.
If I want to outright block the deletion
of the account, I'll have to use the
third setting called block deletion of
GL account.
It works in combination with the date
and the check GL account deletion after
field.
Then,
as my current income year 2023 closes
and I want to keep 5 years of history, I
want to move this date 1 year ahead.
And that's how you can govern the
deletion of GL accounts. Thank you for
watching.